One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Hey! Go get more food!
おい！食料もっと調達してこい
We've got money now!
金はあるんだ！
The booze today is great!
酒がうめえな今日は
No one can top the years I spent graffitiing on walls.
昔っから人んちの壁に よくアートしてたからな
Our money... they took it all.
大金… 全部とられた
Nami...
ナミ…
The crew... I can't face them.
みんなに合わせる顔がねえよ
Give 'em hell, every last one of 'em!
１人残らずぶっ飛ばしてきてよみんな
You sure 'bout that?
そうくるか！
Read 'em and weep!
ほらおめえの負けだ
Now, go get the food!
ほら買い出し行ってこい
Buy up everything at the store, okay?! We've got the money!
店の料理全部買い取ってこいよ 金はあるんだ！
Well, damn! Don't go nowhere, 'cause I'll win next time!
ちくしょう　覚えてろ 後で負かしてやるからな
Huh?
んっ？
What?! What was that?!
何だ？どうした？
Who's there?!
誰かいるぞ！
Who the hell are you?!
誰だてめえら！
That's...
あれは…
Straw Hat Luffy!
麦わらのルフィ！
So you thought you'd come get your money back, huh? How stupid!
金を取り返しに来やがったな？バカめ
You see all of us? What could the four of you possibly do?
この人数を見ろ たった４人でおめえら何しようってんだ？
But, here you are. Word is, you've got a bounty on your head.
だがまあ　来たからにゃあ 賞金の懸かったその首
So why not leave your head with us?
置いてってもらうゴォ
He's that long-nosed wimp's captain!
あの貧弱長っ鼻野郎の船長だ
So he can't be that tough!
実力の程も知れてるってもんだ
Bring it on, short stuff!
来てみろ　チビ
Gum-Gum...
ゴムゴムの…
Huh?
んっ？
What're you doing?
何やってるんだ？
He's using his bare fists? Even a battleship wouldn't put a dent in that thick steel armor!
パンチか　戦艦の砲撃も通じねえ あの巨大鋼鉄アーマーに！
What a joke!
笑わせる！
If you're just gonna fool around, I'll go ahead and crush you.
遊んどるならこっちからたたき潰すゴォ！
...Cannon!
キャノン！
– What?!
–　うがああっ！
H-He busted right through that thick armor!
きょ…　巨大アーマーを貫いたーっ！
Hey!
おい…
N-Now wait a minute, guys! Let's talk things over!
ちょ…　ちょっと待てお前ら まず話を…
Let's talk...
話…
Let's... Let's...
はな…　はな…
Let's fire the cannons!
放て砲弾！
Yahoo!
イヤッホイ！
Three-Sword Style:
三刀流
Dire Raven...
鴉魔
Hunt!
狩り！
Th-These cannonballs are made of iron, you know!
ほっ…　砲弾は鉄なんですけど！
And the cannon?!
だーっ！大砲まで！
Bad news! These guys are seriously bad news!
ヤベえーっ！ ちょっとこいつらマジでヤベえぞ！
L-Let's scram! Get out through the back door!
に…　逃げろ 裏口から逃げるんだ！
You picked this fight. Don't even think about backing out.
人にケンカ売っといて 締まらねえマネすんじゃねえよ
Party Table...
パーティーテーブル…
Kick Course!
キックコース！
B-Back door's a no-go!
うっ…　裏口はダメだ！
The windows! Try the windows!
窓だ　窓から…
Rumble!
ランブル！
Horn Point!
ホーンポイント！
Roseo Colonnade!
ロゼオコロネード！
W-W-Wait a sec, you guys!
ちょっ…　ちょちょ… ちょっと待ってお前ら
It's the money, right?! That's what you want!
金だろ？え？返してほしいのは
The 200 million belly that loser had, right?
あのヘナチョコが持ってた２億ベリーだろ？
Unfortunately, that money isn't here anymore!
残念なことにここにはもう その金はねえんだぜ？
Our boss, Big Bro Franky, took the money and went shopping.
一家の頭フランキーのアニキが あの金持って買い物に出ちまったんだ
He's working a black-market deal, so he could be anywhere by now!
闇取引なんで 俺たちも行き先知らねえし…
Basically, even if you go berserk here, that 200 million belly won't come ba–
つまりここでどれだけ暴れようとも あの２億ベリーはもう戻りゃあしな…
Ahh! Zambai!
うおおっザンバイ！
Stop running your mouth. This was never about the money.
もうしゃべってくれるな そういうこっちゃねえんだよ
Yeah. It's too late.
そうだな　もう手遅れだ
After we're done, not even your bones will remain.
おめえら骨も残らねえと思え
Not even our bones?!
骨もですか！？
You idiot! Don't let 'im scare you!
バカ野郎！ビビんじゃねえ！
"Not even your bones will remain."
骨も残さねえのは
That's our line! We're the Franky Family, professional dismantlers and bounty hunters!
この解体屋兼賞金稼ぎの フランキー一家の言うことだ！
Show 'em the Franky House specialty!
見せてやれ！ フランキーハウス名物！
Anything Goes Cannon!
ナンデモショットキャノン！
Here they come! Take 'em out!
来るぞ！かかれ～っ！
S-Stand tall! Keep firing until we run out of projectiles!
ひっ…　ひるむな！ 砲弾尽きるまで撃ちまくれ
There're only four of 'em!
相手はたかだか４人だ！
Hm?
んっ？
What're those noises? Fireworks?
何だあの音は？花火か？
They're coming from the northeast... That's the Franky House!
島の北東 フランキーハウスのほうからだぞ
Them again? What's the big fuss this time?
またあいつらか… 今度は何の騒ぎだ？
Yeah, it– Shh! He'll hear us!
そうだ…　うっ！ シッ！聞こえるぞ
Oh, great. They're gonna tear the place apart.
あらあらはしゃぎすぎだわいな
It sure as hell ain't no cocktail party.
ホントにあいつらは 底なしのハメ外しだわいな
It's okay once in a while, right? Today's a special day!
たまにはいいじゃねえか 今日はよき日だ
Should we go after Franky?
追うか？フランキー
Where would he be?
どこへだよ
What a pain. Looks like they really don't know where the money is.
参ったな…　金の行方は 本当に分からねえようだ
Even if we strangle this Franky guy, he might've already spent the money.
そのフランキーってヤツを締め上げても 買い物された後じゃな…
What now? We can wait around, but he might not be back for a while.
どうする？ここでそいつを待っても 当分帰っちゃこねえぞ
Hey! I finished giving him first aid!
おい！応急処置終わったぞ
I need him on a stretcher. Give me a hand!
担架で運ぶから手伝ってくれよ
We won't figure it out here.
ここで話しててもしかたねえ
Let's go back to the ship for now. Nami's all alone there.
とにかく船に戻ろう ナミさん１人残してきてるし
There's also Robin...
ロビンちゃんのことも…
and the issues with the ship too.
船自体の問題もある
Yeah.
ああ
Hey, Luffy!
おいルフィ！
About the ship...
船だけどよ…
Hm?
んっ？
I've decided.
決めたよ
This is where we say goodbye to the Going Merry.
ゴーイング･メリー号とは ここで別れよう
Well then, I'll be on my way.
では今日はこれで失礼
I can't believe how stubborn that guy is.
まったく強情な男だ
We don't even know if he has it, but they keep sending me out here anyway.
しかし本当に持っているのかどうかも分からんのに こんな所まで毎度遣わされる
I wish they'd put themselves in my shoes.
私の身にもなってほしいもんだ…
It's Kalifa.
カリファです
Well... come in.
ンマー入れ
You must be worn out, Mr. Iceburg.
お疲れさまでした　アイスバーグさん
Something to drink?
お飲み物でも…
Yeah.
そうだな…
Today, tea would be–
今日は紅茶を…
Already brewed.
いれてきました
Well, that's just like you, Kalifa.
ンマーさすがだなカリファ
Thank you very much.
恐れ入ります
Mr. Corgi tends to leave in a bad mood, doesn't he?
コーギー氏はいつも怒ってお帰りですね
What in the world does he come to ask you?
一体何のご相談なんです？
Oh, that.
ああ
He wants something I have, so he comes to persuade me to give it up.
俺の持ち物を欲しがって いろいろと条件を出してくる
It must be something very precious, huh?
何か大切なものなんですね
Well, you see... I just tell him I don't know what he's talking about and stonewall him.
まあな　そんなものは知らんと いつも突き返してる
He's such a pain in the butt.
まったく面倒くせえヤツらだ
Ah!
あっ！
Hey! Usopp woke up!
おーい！ ウソップが目を覚ましたぞ！
Really?! That's great!
ホントか！よかった～
Now we can relax a little.
これでひと安心ね
Hey, Usopp!
おーいウソップ！
Robin isn't back yet.
帰らねえなロビンちゃんは
Seriously, you shouldn't worry us like that!
もう… あまり心配させないでよね
She's right. Marching in there by yourself was reckless.
本当だぜ １人で乗り込むなんてまったくムチャしやがる
You're lucky to be alive.
命があったからよかったものの
Think before you act next time.
少しは考えて動けよ
Look who's talking!
お前が言うか！そのセリフ
I'm sorry for being such a screw-up!
俺がふがいねえばっかりにすまねえ
I mean it...
ホント…
I'm such a failure!
面目ねえ
You guys!
みんな！
That money meant so much, and I let it... I let it...
大事な金を 俺は…　俺は！
Whoa, wait! Cool it! I-I get it already, so let go!
ちょっと待て…　落ち着けよ 分かったから放せよ！
No really, we went through so much to get that money and I...
だけど…　せっかく 手に入れたとんでもねえ大金を！
Usopp, you should still be in bed.
ウソップまだ寝てなきゃダメだよ
Hey, you need to listen to Chopper.
ほら　もう チョッパーの言うこと聞きなさいって
Then that's that.
じゃあやっぱり
The money is gone for good, huh?
金は戻らねえのか
Well, we won't know for sure until this Franky guy comes back.
いやあそれもフランキーってのが 帰ってこねえと分かんねえんだ
I see. I'm sorry.
そうか…　すまねえ
But even if we don't get it back, we still have 100 million belly.
まあもしダメでもよ まだ１億ベリーあるんだから
So it's okay. No worries.
いいよ　気にすんな
It's not okay! That's our money!
よくないわよお金は！
Nami...
ナミ
Ah! My bad.
あっ…　ああごめん
No, she's right.
いや　いいんだ
Anyway, Luffy, what about the ship? What about the Merry?
だけどルフィ 船は…　メリー号は…
Will the remaining 100 million be enough for her repairs?
その…　残った１億で 何とか直せるのか？
We're lucky we're at a first-class shipyard that can fix her up.
せっかくこんな一流の造船所で 修理できるんだ
We'll have to refit her so she can weather the seas ahead.
この先の海も渡っていけるように 今まで以上に強い船に
Usopp, about that...
ウソップ船はよ
We're getting a new ship.
乗り換えることにしたんだ
Sorry I didn't talk to you about it first,
お前のいないとこで決めちまって 悪かったと思ってる
but I've already made up my mind.
けどもう決めたんだ
The Going Merry took good care of us, but our journey with her ends here.
ゴーイング･メリー号には世話になったけど この船での航海はここまでだ
Anyway...
ほんでな
I took a look at the catalog Iceboss gave us.
アイスのおっさんのとこで もらってきたカタログでよ
There're loads of different ships to check out in here.
新しく買える船を調べてたら 結構いろんなのがあんだな～
If we go with a used one, 100 million should get us a way bigger ship.
まあ　１億もあれば 中古でも今よりでけえ船が…
Hold it...
待てよ
Just hold it, please.
待て　待て
This joke... You're taking things a little too far. Don't you think?
そんなお前…　冗談キツいぞ ばかばかしい　なあ？
I mean, look! Chopper's taking it seriously.
ほら見ろ チョッパーのヤツ真に受けちまったじゃねえか
Really though, someone tell our captain to cut it out already.
まったく困ったもんだぜ うちの船長さんはよ
Say something to him, Nami.
何か言ってやれよナミ
So then... we really don't... have enough money to repair her?
何だ？やっぱり修理代 足りなくなったってことか？
It's because I let them steal the 200 million, isn't it?!
俺があいつらにあの２億とられちまったからか… 金が足りなくなったんだろ？
Hey, that's what's going on, right, Luffy?
なあそうなんだろ？ルフィ！
A world-class shipyard would charge premium prices, after all...
一流の造船所は やっぱ取る金額も一流で…
No! That's not it!
違うよ！そうじゃねえ！
Then what is it?! Spit it out! Are you sugarcoating this for my sake?!
おいじゃあ何だ？はっきり言えよ！ 俺に気使ってんのか！
I'm not! This has nothing to do with the money getting stolen!
使わねえよ！ あの金がとられたことは関係ねえんだ！
Then why the harebrained plan to get a new ship?!
だったら何で乗り換えるなんて くだらねえこと言うんだ！
Hey, stop it, you two!
おい！やめろ２人とも！
What good will bickering do? Calm down, then talk!
言い争ってどうなるんだ？ もっと落ち着いて話をしろ！
How can I calm down after hearing this bullshit?!
落ち着いてられるか！ バカなこと言いだしやがって
Hey! I get that this is important, but you shouldn't get so worked up.
ちょっと 大事な話なんだから熱くならないで
She's right, Usopp. You'll get worse if you don't take it easy.
そうだよウソップ 安静にしてなきゃダメだよ　体に障るよ
So then, I get worse!
体なんて知るか！
I can't relax when the captain casually says we'll get a new ship!
船長に簡単に乗り換えるなんて 言われて黙ってられるかよ！
I wasn't being casual! I decided after agonizing over it!
簡単じゃねえ！ ちゃんと俺だって悩んで決めたんだ！
And what exactly agonized you about this decision?!
何をどう悩んだらこうなるんだ！
You've got some nerve to spout off while waving this around!
こんなもんちらつかせて そんな話すんじゃねえよ！
Why'd you do that?!
何すんだお前！
It was pissing me off.
目障りなんだよ
Tell me, Luffy, if it's not about the stolen money, then what is it about?!
おいルフィ　金をとられたからじゃねえってんなら どういう訳だ！
Huh, Luffy?! Just say it already! Hey! Why won't you tell me?!
ああ？ルフィ！言ってみろよほら！ 何黙ってんだよ！
Don't hold back, no matter how much it stings!
俺に気使ってねえってなら 遠慮すんなよ！
Say it! Why should I go along with this?! Huh?!
言えよ！ちゃんとした理由もなしに 俺は納得なんかしねえぞ　おい！
The Merry can't...
メリー号はもう…
What was... What did you just say?
今…　何て言った？
Don't make me repeat myself.
何度も言わせんじゃねえよ
The Merry... can't be repaired.
メリー号はもう直せねえんだ
There's just... no way to fix her.
どうしても直らねえんだ
If there were, I wouldn't be talking like this.
そうじゃなきゃこんな話しねえ
This ship?! You mean the ship we're aboard right now?!
この船だぞ！ 今俺たちが乗ってるこの船だぞ！
That's right. This ship won't last much longer.
そうだ もう沈むんだこの船は
What're you saying, Luffy?
何言ってんだお前…　ルフィ
It's the truth. They told us at the shipyard.
本当なんだ そう言われたんだ　造船所で
They said she won't even reach the next island.
もう次の島にも行き着けねえって
Is that so? She won't, huh?
そうかい 行き着けねえって…
You just met these guys today, and they've already convinced you to walk away?
今日会ったばかりの他人に 説得されて帰ってきたのかよ
Say what?
何だと？
I get that these top-notch shipwrights gave you their assessment, but...
一流と言われる船大工たちが もうダメだって言っただけで
you gave up just like that?!
お前は帰ってきたのかよ！
We've traveled together all this time!
今までずっと一緒に海を旅してきた！
Past every wave! Through every battle!
どんな波も戦いも
She's a precious member of this crew!
一緒に切り抜けてきた大事な仲間を
And you're just gonna abandon her in a place like this?!
お前はこんなとこで見殺しにする気か！
So that's it... Is that how little this ship means to you, Luffy?!
この船はお前にとっちゃ そんくらいのもんなのかよルフィ！
You shouldn't shout like that, Usopp.
ダメだよウソップ そんなに叫んじゃ
Please, step aside.
悪いがどいてろ
What?
えっ？
I haven't gotten through to him yet.
まだ話はついてねえんだ
Usopp...
ウソップ
Then can you make a more accurate assessment?!
じゃあお前に判断できんのかよ
We don't have our own shipwright. That's why we got those guys to check her out!
この船には 船大工がいねえから… だからあいつらに見てもらったんじゃねえか
I get it, but asking guys like them to fix her is pointless!
だったらいいよ もうそんなヤツらに頼まなきゃいい
I'll repair her like I always have!
今までどおり俺が修理してやるよ
After all, that's how we made it this far.
もともとそうやって 旅を続けてきたんだもんな
Alright! No time like the present! Give me a hand, you guys!
よし　早速始めよう おい　お前ら手伝えよ
Hey, wait, Usopp.
おい　待てウソップ
Oh, yeah, we don't have enough lumber. I'll go buy some at the shipyard.
ああそうだ　木材が足りねえな 造船所で買ってこよう
Now, we've got a lot to do.
さあ忙しくなってきた
You're not a shipwright, Usopp!
お前は船大工じゃねえだろウソップ！
Hold on, Luffy!
ちょっとルフィ！
Yeah, you're right. So what?!
おうそうだよ それがどうした！
I don't trust shady shipwrights who abuse their position
だがな職人の立場をいいことに
and write things off because it's "just another ship" to them!
しょせんは他人の船をあっさりと見限るような 無責任な船大工なんか俺は信じねえ！
Usopp...
ウソップ
The lesson here...? We need to look out for the ship ourselves.
自分たちの船は 自分たちで守れって教訓だなこりゃ
I'll never give up on this ship!
絶対に 俺は見捨てねえぞ この船を！
Did you lose your minds?!
バカか？お前ら
You all got taken in by those smooth-talking shipwrights, didn't you?!
おおかた船大工のもっともらしい 正論に担がれてきたんだろ
The Luffy I know wouldn't have fallen for some sales pitch.
俺の知ってるお前らなら そんなヤツらの商売口上より
He would've been the first to believe in the Merry's strength!
このメリー号の強さをまず信じたはずだ
But you didn't hesitate, acting like some wise geezer with all the answers.
そんな歯切れのいい 悟りきった年寄りじみた答えで
What kind of captain makes snap decisions like that?!
船長風吹かせて何が決断だ
I was wrong about you, Luffy!
見損なったぞルフィ！
Wait a sec, Usopp! Luffy thought the same–
ちょっと待ってよウソップ ルフィだって…
Stay out of this, Nami! This is something only I decided!
黙ってろナミ！ これは俺が決めたことだ
And I won't budge.
意見は変えねえ
No matter what you say, we're getting a new ship!
今更お前が何つったって 船は乗り換える
We'll say goodbye to the Merry here!
メリー号とはここで別れるんだ！
Like hell we will! I can't accept that!
ふざけんな！ そんなことは許さねえ！
Listen, Luffy! Not everyone shares your carefree attitude!
いいかルフィ　誰でもてめえみたいに前ばっかり 向いて生きていけるわけじゃねえ
I can't just leave our wounded friend here and move on to the seas ahead!
俺は傷ついた仲間を置き去りに この先の海へなんて進めねえ！
Don't give me that! Friend or not, humans and ships are different!
バカ言え 仲間でも人間と船じゃ話が違う！
They're the goddamn same! Merry still has some fight in her!
同じだ！ メリーだって生きたいっていう底力はある！
But knowing you, you're probably just excited about getting a new ship.
お前のことだもう次の船に気持ちを 移してワクワクしてんじゃねえのか
You can't work this out if you're all fired up!
おいお前ら大概にしろ そんなに熱くなってちゃ話にならねえだろ！
Don't pretend to care about the Merry!
上っ面だけメリーを思ったふりしてよ！
Enough already!
いいかげんにしろお前！
Luffy!
ルフィ！
You're not the only one hurting over this!
お前だけがつらいなんて思うなよ
Everyone here feels the same!
全員気持ちは おんなじなんだ！
If that were true, there's no way you'd get a new ship!
だったら乗り換えるなんて答えが出るはずねえ！
Fine! If you hate how I run things, you should just lea–
じゃあいいさ　そんなに俺のやり方が 気に入らねえんなら今すぐこの船…
Sanji!
サンジ
You damn idiot. What were you about to say?!
バカ野郎が てめえ今何言おうとしたんだ！
Cool down before you end up saying something you'll regret! Got that, Luffy?!
頭冷やせ！めったなこと口にするんじゃねえぞ 分かってんのかルフィ！
Sorry. I just...
悪かった　今のはつい…
That's okay, Luffy. That's probably how you really feel.
いや　いいんだルフィ それがお前の本心だろ
What'd you say?!
何だと？
Just get rid of the useless crewmates that hold you back.
使えねえ仲間は 次々に切り捨てて先へ進めばいい
If you're gonna abandon the Merry...
メリー号に見切りをつけるんなら
why not do the same with me?!
俺にもそうしろよ
Hey, Usopp. Quit talking like that.
おいウソップ くだらねえこと言ってんじゃねえぞ
No, I'm serious.
いや　本気だ
It's been on my mind for a while.
前々から考えていた
To be honest, I've been thinking that I can't keep up with how monstrous you all are.
正直俺はもうお前らの化け物じみた強さには ついていけねえと思ってた
Like today, I couldn't even guard the money.
今日みてえに ただの金の番すらろくにできねえ
I'll just continue to be a burden on you guys.
この先もまた おめえらに迷惑かけるだけだ俺は
You don't need weak crew members, right?
弱え仲間はいらねえんだろ？
Luffy, you're the man who'll be King of the Pirates.
ルフィ お前は海賊王になる男だもんな
But I don't feel the need to go that far.
俺は何も そこまで高みへ行けなくていい
Thinking back on it, I was about to sail off on my own, when you invited me to join you.
思えば俺が海へ出ようとした時に お前らが船に誘ってくれた
What're you talking about? Get on already.
何言ってんだよ　早く乗れよ
You're one of us now, aren't you?
俺たちもう仲間だろ？
That's all that binds us.
それだけの縁だ
If we can't see eye to eye, then why should we travel together?!
意見が食い違ってまで 一緒に旅をすることはねえよ！
Hey, where're you going, Usopp?!
おい どこ行くんだウソップ
Where I'm going is my own business.
どこへ行こうと俺の勝手
It has nothing to do with you guys anymore.
もうお前らには関係ない
I'm...
俺は…
leaving the crew.
この一味を　やめる
Why... Why aren't you saying anything?
何で何も言わないのよ
Usopp!
ウソップ！
Wait! This is all wrong!
待ってよ　こんなのダメよ！
Hey! Turn around!
ねえ！引き返して！
Hey! Come back!
おい！戻れ！
Don't go, Usopp!
行かないでくれよウソップ！
Come back!
戻ってきてよ！
Luffy...!
ルフィ
Luffy! I can't follow you anymore.
お前とはもうやっていけねえ
Sorry I dragged you down till the end.
最後まで迷惑かけたな
I realize that the ship belongs to you, the captain.
確かにその船は 船長であるお前のもんだ
So fight me for her...
だから俺と戦え
Monkey D. Luffy!
モンキー･Ｄ･ルフィ
I challenge you to a duel!
俺と決闘しろー！
What? What? H-Hey... What're you saying?!
えっえっ？ねえちょっと… 何言ってんの？
At ten o'clock tonight, I'll come back here.
今夜10時 また俺はここへ戻ってくる
Then we'll have a duel for the Merry!
そしたらメリー号を懸けて決闘だ
I'll defeat you and take her!
お前を倒してメリー号はもらっていく
And then...
それで…
there'll be nothing left to bind us.
俺とお前たちとの縁も終わりだ